Srinivasan Thathankudi Chakkarapani

Digital Product Designer (UI-UX)

www.srinivasan.design

+1 312-973-6557

tcsreeni93@gmail.com

Summary

A passionate full spectrum product designer with 3 years of experience in designing and shipping digital products for Food Tech, Fin Tech & SaaS companies. I'm an advocate for functional, aesthetic and user-centred products which has an impact on people's life solving a need. I have a strong notion that a good product is a concoction of design and technology.

Professional Experience

User Experience Design Intern | Google

June 2019 - September 2019

Designed and shipped the first version of design system for Google Ad Manager. Primarily worked on the component library from audit to shipping a library of reusable components for designers in the team. Worked closely with the visual design lead, a senior interaction designer to define the component design process and standardize the elements. The design system imporved the consistency of the product and the velocity of designers workflow.

Interaction Designer | Zeta

February 2018 - August 2018

Improved the visual design and user experience of the leave travel allowance program in zeta optima. Worked on two stealth mode products which focuses on digitising the tax benefits for employers & employees on web and mobile platforms by ideating, conceptualizing and designing the product.

Product Designer | Zoho Corporation

December 2015 - January 2018

Designed and shipped the first version of Zoho Sheet product on mobile platforms as the primary product designer. I worked on designing the application for iOS and Android platforms from ideating features, wireframing to high fidelity mocks and framing a design system. Worked closely with the developers, product managers to effectively ship the product to the respective application stores which onboard many web application users to the mobile platforms.

Product Designer | Holachef

June 2015 - December 2015

Designed and shipped the second version of the iOS and Android Application for the company. Collaborated with the product design lead to redesign the primary web product. Designed the mobile applications for chefs and delivery executives to ease their work which also helped in fuctioning of the business.

Education

Masters in Human Computer Interaction

DePaul University - June 2020

Bachelors in Computer Science

SASTRA University - 2015

Key Skills

Information Architecture

Wireframing

Interaction Design

Visual Design

Prototyping

Motion Design

Usablity Testing

Design Systems

User Research

Product Strategy

Competitve analysis

Journey Mapping

Tools

Wireframing

Balsamiq, Axure RP.

Design

Sketch, Adobe Photoshop Illustrator & XD, Figma.

Prototyping

Principle, Adobe After Effects, Framer X, Marvel, Invision.

Development

HTML, CSS, Javascript.